快點 快點 Sophia 親愛的
Come on. Come on. Sophia. Honey.
- 媽媽都餵你什麼了? - 你真行 給女兒灌輸體重情結呀
- What is mommy feeding you? - Oh,nice. Give our daughter a weight complex.
- 你有體重情結麼? - 有~
- Do you have a weight complex? - Yes.
進去吧
Let's go inside.
"即使我在困苦中迷途 你仍延續著我的生活"
"though I wal in the midst of trouble, "you preserve my life.
"你伸手護我 抵抗敵人的怒火"
"you stretch out your hand against the anger of my foes,
"你用你的右手拯救了我 上帝的意旨"
"and with your right hand,you save me. The word of the lord."
感謝上帝
Thanks be to god.
上帝之身
The body of christ.
- 上帝之身 - 阿門
- The body of christ. - Amen.
- 上帝之身 - 上帝之血
- The body of christ. - The blood of christ.
阿門
Amen.
爸爸 我能喝一點嗎?
Daddy,can I have some of that?
21歲之後才行 或者 等你的第一次聖餐之後
Not till you're 21 Or your first communion.
- 媽媽 我的娃娃... - 好了 我先幫你拿著
- Mommy,my doll-- - Ok,I'm taking this away from you.
- 不行! - 好 好 但現在不是玩的時候
- No! - Hey,ok,now is not the time to play.
聖餐之後 我們要向基督傾訴
After communion,we talk to jesus.
- 我不要跟基督說話 - 試著說說
- I don't want to talk to jesus! - Well,try.
我知道這不容易 但如果你試著用心傾訴
Listen,I know it's hard, but if you really try...
親愛的? 親愛的?
Honey? Honey?
救命! 天啊! 救命! 來人啊! 救命啊!
Help! Oh,god! Please! Somebody help me! Somebody,please!
來人啊救命! 來人啊! 來人啊救命!
Please help me! Please! Please help me!
- 爸爸你沒事吧? - 有人是醫生嗎?
- Daddy,are you all right? - Is anyone a doctor?
打911!
Call 911!
不! 趕緊把你女兒帶走! 快!
Oh,no! Take your daughter away! Now!
寶貝! 寶貝 走吧! 來這邊 走吧 走吧 快點
Baby! Baby,come here! Come here. Come here. Come here. Come on.
Paul! Paul! 快打911!
Paul! Paul! Call 911!
這是Paul Collins上尉
This is captain paul collins.
他是羅得島 普羅維頓斯 兩周之內第三個受害者了
He's the third victim in 2 weeks In providence,rhode island.
- 上尉? - 對 他四去伊拉克服役 兩周前剛回來
- Captain? - Yeah,he just returned home 2 weeks ago From his fourth tour in iraq.
被授勳為戰鬥英雄
He's a decorated war hero.
他是因為軍隊出身 才被當做目標的嗎?
Was he targeted because he's in the military?
不 跟前兩個受害者一樣 殺他們是因為容易被殺
No. Just like the first two victims, he was targeted because he was convenient.
他是在教堂做禮拜的時候被殺的
He was killed at a church during an early service.
頸部被割開 頸動脈瞬間大出血
Bled out in a matter of moments.
就在他女兒面前
Right in front of his daughter.
在教堂殺人 很有象徵性
Murder in a church is highly symbolic.
是否牽扯到什麼宗教爭議?
Is there a religious agenda involved?
鑒於前兩名受害者情況 負責調查的 Jake Moreland警探把這一原因排除
The detective on the case,jake moreland, Ruled that out because of the first two victims.
第一個受害者Mike O'Donnell 死於一餐廳男廁的洗手盆下面
The first victim,mike o'donnell,was found Under a sink in the men's room at a restaurant.
什麼樣的餐廳?
What kind of restaurant?
本地餐廳 白桌布 佐餐酒
Local place,white tablecloths and jug wine.
第二個受害者 Karen Lagrassa 是在洗衣店被殺的
The second victim,karen lagrassa, was killed at the laundromat.
三個人都是喉嚨被割開
All 3 had their throats slashe.
拋開辦案手法不說 這些受害者都是隨機的
Aside from m.O.,the victimology's all over the place.
兇手根本不在乎殺的是什麼人 只在乎行兇手段
It's like this guy doesn't care who he's killing, Just how.
並且都是在公開場合 根本不擔心被旁人看見
And he's doing it in public Without compunction for who sees him.
有外貌素描嗎?
Do we have a sketch?
大家都一致的說法 就只有 白種男人 25到40歲之間
All anyone can agree on Is that it's a white male between 25 and 40.
這下好了 範圍縮小到  普羅維頓斯的所有男人
Well,that narrows it down to all of providence.
我們也不能怪目擊者 謀殺實在太血腥了
Hard to fault the witnesses given how bloody these murders must be.
他殺人的間隔越來越短 使我很不安
What bothers me is the cooling off period Is getting shorter and shorter,
他完全不躲藏 不掩飾自己的行為
With no attempt to hide who he is or what he's doing.
不明嫌犯那麼大膽  很可能正遭受精神崩潰
I mean,an unsub this bold could be suffering from a major psychotic break.
我已經叫Moreland警探調出 最近釋放的犯人和精神病人的資料
I already asked detective moreland to pull recent releases On prisons and mental hospitals.
我們得盡快趕去普羅維頓斯
We need to get to providence asap.
不論是不是精神崩潰  這很可能只是他殺人序幕的開始
Whether he's suffering a psychotic break or not, This could be the start of a spree.
任何人都有可能成為被害者
And anyone is a potential target.
犯罪心理 第五季 第15集 全民公敵
Criminal Minds Season05 Episode15 Public Enemy
"給我一位英雄 我還你一齣悲劇"
"show me a hero And I will write you tragedy."
美國小說家 F. Scott Fitzgerald
F.Scott fitzgerald.
他為什麼要用刀?
Why is he using a knife?
用槍可以殺更多的人
Guns assure the highest number of fatalities.
如果他只關心殺人數量 大可以做得更有效率一點
If all he's interested in is quantity, He could be doing this more efficiently.
他可能是在練手
He could be training.
殺人狂在開始瘋狂行兇前 都會練練手
Spree killers often to dry runs Before they start their rampage.
大多數殺人狂 一開始殺人就會失去控制
Most spree killers have lost control by the time they begin.
通常為男性 如果不是什麼校園殺手的話
They're always male. And if they don't fall into the school shooter category,
他們會更老一點 四五十歲 不與別人來往
They're older,40s and 50s, socially isolated.
行兇的導火索 通常是在社會上再也混不下去了
The stressor's usually the dissolution Of their last social outlet.
George Hennard 受James Huberty啟發
George hennard was inspired by james huberty.
兩人在快餐店一共射殺43人
Between the two of them,they shot 43 people at fast food restaurants.
如果他正為大範圍屠殺做準備的話 一定會越來越大膽
Well,if he's practicing for his mass murder, He's definitely getting bolder about it.
也更血腥
And bloodier.
現在 人們的震驚和恐懼正讓他無比享受
Right now,the shock and awe of the bloodletting Seems to be what he's going for.
但很快 他就會感到不滿足
But soon,that won't be enough.
那這就和他的幻想生活有關了
That makes sense with regards to his fantasy life.
如果他正計劃什麼大動作 肯定會成天沉浸在想像中
If he is planning something big, He'll spend his day dreaming of it,
在真實和想像中實施著自己的報復計劃
Getting back at slights both real and imagined.
沒有特定的殺人目標
Without a specific target victim,
我們得專注於犯罪現場 發掘有用的信息
We need to concentrate on the crime scenes And see what they tell us.
Prentiss 你負責自助洗衣店
Prentiss,you take the laundromat.
我讓Moreland警探到那兒跟你會合
I'll have detective moreland meet you there.
- 不介意的話 我想去看一下事發教堂 - 好的
- I'd like to take a look at the church If you don't mind. - Good.
JJ和Morgan 去和Collins隊長的妻子談談
Jj,you and morgan Interview captain collins' wife.
她最有可能看清不明嫌犯 問問她還記得什麼
She got the best look at the unsub. See what she remembers.
Reid和我去警察局獲得線索
Reid and I will run point from the police station.
- Rossi探員? - 您肯定是Kendellen神父
- Agent rossi? - You must be father kendellen.
謝謝你能及時趕來
Thank you for coming so quickly.
這是我們應該做的 神父
It's the lst we can do,father.
實話說 我一直努力想去理解這一切
To be honest, I've been struggling to understand all this.
這太讓人... 難以接受了
It's been... Trying.
我都不想在教堂門前看到警戒線
I don't like to see crime tape In front of church doors.
難以想像您現在的感受
I can't imagine how you feel.
下周就是聖灰日了 (復活節前的第七個星期三)
Ash Wednesday's next week.
這堛漯糷應該對公眾緊閉的
These doors should never be closed to the community.
說實話 Hotchner警探 他們說BAU要來
To be honest,agent hotchner, When they told me bau was coming,
我想 一定不止兩名探員吧
I expected more than two agents.
其他的探員直接去現場了
The rest of the agents went straight to the crime scenes.
我相信現場一定有線索 能確定不明嫌犯的下一個目標
I believe there'll be information there That may determine where the unsub will strike next.
請你盡快去洗衣店與Prentiss會合
As soon as you can,I'd like you to meet Agent prentiss at the laundromat.
好 沒問題
Yeah,sure.
能想到下一次行兇會在哪兒嗎? 我們可以派兩班人員加強巡邏
Any idea on where he may hit next? We can double patrols.
老實說 現在還不好確定
It's honestly too early to tell.
你的直覺一定告訴了你什麼
Well,your gut must be telling you something.
目前 他在餐廳洗手間 洗衣店和教堂下手
Well,this far,he's struck at a restaurant bathroom, A laundromat,and a church.
他不是根據自身喜好挑選受害者 只挑有利的環境
He chooses his victims not out of preference, But of favorable circumstance.
每殺一次 他就變得更大膽 這說明他不在乎被別人看到
With each kill he's growing bolder, Telling us he doesn't care who sees him.
- 所以下一次可能發生在人更多的地方 - 是的
- So next time it'll be even more public. - Yes.
我們的技術分析員會列出一系列 社會活動 你們部門應進行監視
Our technical analyst Is compiling a list of public events That your department should be monitoring.
Garcia 在嗎?
Garcia,aryou there?
- 聲音清楚 聽候調遣 - 現在有什麼進展?
- Wired for sound and ready for action. - What have you got so far?
"冰上芝麻街" 哈萊姆籃球表演
Well,you got your "sesame street on ice," Your harlem globetrotters,
披頭士翻唱樂隊演出 還有許多大學酒吧
your beatles cover bands, Not to mention the dozens of college bars
以及美國小青年經常光顧的 各種午夜娛樂場所
And late-night hangouts frequented by the youth of america.
- 沒有特別的大事 沒有特別的小事 - 好的 繼續
- No event is too big or too small. - Good. Keep going.
是 是 隊長
Aye,aye,cap'n.
都到這份上了 還一點不尊重死者
No respect,even now.
- 我負責說話 - 無可奉告 無可奉告 無可奉告
- I do the talking. - No comment,no comment,no comment.
FBI為什麼參與Collins上尉遇害的調查?
What's the fbi's involment in the investigation In the murder of captain collins?
無可奉告
No comment.
我們只是來協助普羅維頓斯警部的調查
We are strictly here Just to advise the providence police department.
Collins隊長遇害 和上周兩起 被刺案件有沒有聯繫呢?
Is the collins murder tied to the other two stabbings of last week?
警局發佈消息的時候 大家就會知道了 謝謝
And when they are ready to make their statement, They'll let you know. Thank you.
他們在外面一整天了
They've been out there all day.
我的一些朋友本想過來 可都不想上6點的夜新聞
Some of my friends wanted to come by, They didn't want to be on the 6:00 news.
你的丈夫是個英雄
Your husband's a hero.
很遺憾 他的死成為了媒體關注的焦點
Unfortunately, The circumstances of his death Has caused this to be a media circus.
他們就不能表現出一點點的...
Well,you'd think they'd show a little--
我怎麼和你說的 Sophia? 離窗戶遠點
What did I tell you,sophia? Get away from the window.
我們會上電視嗎?
Are we going to be on tv?
我不會讓我們上電視的 去你的房間玩 我一會兒去
Not if I can help it. Go in your room and play. I'll be there in a sec.
我盼了多少年 盼著接到一通電話  或是那種他們親自送來
I spent years waiting for a phone call Or one of those letters they used to hand-deliver
遞交給犧牲戰士妻子的光榮信
To dead soldiers' wives.
他們問我是否想要把Paul埋在 埋在阿林頓國家公墓 但我沒有...
They want to know if I want to bury paul At--at arlington, But I don't have--
好了
Ok.
我知道你們來這兒有工作
I know you have a job to do.
那麼開始吧 就按正確的程序走
Let's do this so it's done right.
Paul也會這麼說的
That's what paul would say.
你們需要瞭解些什麼?
What do you need to know?
兇案就在這媯o生的
It happened right here.
你跟警察說你不知道 不明疑犯什麼時候進來的?
You told the police you weren't sure When the unsub walked in?
是的
Yes.
我不知道
I don't know.
之前他還不在的 突然就出現了
One ment he wasn't there,and then he was.
好吧 我們回顧一下彌撒的過程
All right,let's walk through the mass.
你跟警察說你們去晚了
You told the police that you were late.
在讀聖經的時候 他們進來的
They came in during the first reading.
- 大部分教友長什麼樣 你都記得? - 是的
- You know most of your parishioners on sight? - Yes.
- 但你不認識不明疑犯 對嗎? - 是的
- But not the unsub,right? - No.
我不知怎麼的 沒留意到他
I don't know how I could have missed him.
你跟Collins一家私下挺熟 是嗎?
You know the collins family personally,right?
當然 Paul是在這學校長大的
Of course. I mean,paul,he grew up at this school.
無論他何時回家 他都會來做彌撒
Whenever he came home, he made sure to come to mass.
他們坐在後排 以免打擾其他人?
And they sat there in the back So as not to disturb the mass?
是的
Yes.
他們坐下後 你能看到他們嗎?
Once they were settled, Could you see them?
不能
No.
那麼 神父 你可以釋懷了
Then let yourself off the hook,father.
如果你看不到Collins一家  你也看不到兇手
If you couldn't see the collins family, You couldn't see the killer.
- 不 - 但聖餐的時候 他已經在了?
- No. - But he was definitely there by communion?
- 是的 - 聖餐前不在?
- Yes. - Not before?
- 我不大記得了 - 好吧
- I don't remember. - All right.
Meg 我們可以停一下  如果你想休息的話
Meg,we can take a break If you need to take a break.
怎麼了 寶貝?
What is it,sweetie?
- 我跟他握手了 - 什麼時候?
- I shook his hand. - When was that?
當大家說"祝你平安"的時候  然後大家互相握手
When we all say,"peace be with you" And we shake hands.
然後 我就跟他握手了
I shook his hand.
沒錯 她說的沒錯
That's right. She's right.
在象徵平安的時刻
During the sign of the peace.
他碰了我的孩子 他...
He touched my baby.He--
哦 上帝啊 他...他碰了我的孩子
Oh,god. He t--he touched my baby.
Meg 我知道這對你來說很痛苦
Meg,I know this is difficult.
但是 我希望你能夠集中注意力  再試一下 好嗎? 挺住
But I want you to try and focus. Ok? Stay with me.
我要你告訴我 聖餐過程中發生了什麼
I need you to tell me what happened during communion.
- 我們都站起來了 - 誰第一個站起來的 Paul?
- We all got up. - Who got out first,paul?
是的
Yes.
但他讓我和Sophia先走
But he let me and sophia Go first.
Paul總是走在最後一個
Paul always goes last.
領完聖餐後 我們回到座位 然後我們...
We--we took communion And we--we went back and we,uh...
- 我們... - 沒關係
- We... - That's ok.
我們快結束了 你做得很好
We're almost done. You're doing great.
Paul在你右邊
Paul was on your right.
Sophia在你左邊 然後呢?
Sophia was on your left. What happened?
她自顧自地玩
She was playing.
"聖餐之後 你要祈禱"
And after communion,you pray.
我彎下身 跟她這麼說
I leaned down and I told her that.
所以你一直面向左側  而背對著Paul 背對著兇手
So you were facing to your left,away from paul, Away from the killer.
你沒有看到他怎麼來的  沒有看到他怎麼走的
You never see him coming, you never see him go.
- 我要休息一下 - 好的
- I need a break. - Of course.
我想留在這兒 Meg可能會想起...
I want to stay here. Meg might recall...
更多的東西 即便想不起 她所經歷的一切...
More,and even if she doesn't, What she's going through...
怎麼了?
What's wrong?
這個不明疑犯沒有精神病  也不會開始大屠殺
This unsub isn't psychotic And he's not gonna go on a spree.
他太有耐心了
He's too patient.
好的 但是... 他想要實現什麼目的?
Ok,but... What is he trying to accomplish?
我不知道
I don't know.
把東西拿出來...
Get the stuff out...
好了 我在疊衣服...
All right,I'm folding...
- 你走近 我沒有聽到 - 你總這樣自言自語麼?
- I don't hear you approaching. - You always talk to yourself?
如果這些洗衣機正在運轉  我肯定聽不到你從背後靠近我
Good. If these machines were on, I definitely wouldn't hear you come up behind me.
Jake Moreland 普羅維頓斯警局
Jake moreland,providence p.D.
Emily Prentiss  好極了 你能再走一遍麼?
Emily prentiss. Great. Can you do that again?
- 當然 - 好的
- Sure. - Ok.
你從後門進來  割了我的喉嚨 走了出去
You come in through the back door, Slash my throat,walk out.
房子堨~都沒有監視器
There's no cameras inside or outside of the building.
所有的犯罪現場都一樣
The same is true for all the crime scenes.
這意味著你夠聰明  能把這些都算在你的襲擊計劃之內
Which means you're smart enough to plan for that in your attacks.
卻又夠粗心 斷了你脖子之後 把刀丟在10尺之內
But,careless enough to drop a knife 10 feet After I cut you.
- 但沒留下任何指紋 - 也是
- But you didn't leave any fingerprints. - No.
三個犯罪現場 都是這麼幹的
He did that at all 3 crime scenes.
殺人狂們通常會崇拜自己的兇器
Mass murderers and spree killers, They often fetishize their weapons,
但這傢伙卻拋棄他的兇器 為什麼呢?
But this guy discards his.Why?
只要他想 隨時都能搞到把新刀
He can get a new knife anytime he wants.
軍品店都有買這玩意
They carry these at army/navy stores.
- 這可能是一種引起恐慌的手段 - 怎麼說?
- It could be a scare tactic. - Hoso?
比起槍 美國人更害怕發現有刀子
Americans typically are more terrified By the presence of a knife than a gun.
比如 對大多數強姦受害者來說
如果兇手有槍 他們更可能會大聲呼救
They're more likely to scream out for help if they see a gun,
而如果看到的是刀 則會順從
Whereas they'll comply if they see a blade.
所以 被害者是什麼樣 用什麼兇器 對這個傢伙來說都不重要
So,victimology and murder weapon Aren't important to this guy.
這樣就剩下了什麼呢? 他要襲擊的到底是什麼?
What does that leave? What is he attacking?
就是犯罪現場了
The crime scene itself.
你看見門外的店標了嗎 這家店是什麼時候開的?
Did you see the sign outside when this place was established?
- 1967年 - 跟那家餐館一樣
- 1967. - The same as the restaurant.
意大利館子傳到第二代了
Second generation italian.
這社區的人都去那埵Y東西
Everyone in the neighborhood eats there.
聖阿爾維納教堂是上世紀初建的
St.Alvina's was built at the beginning of the last century.
三處現場 在這個社區堻ㄕ鳥史
So each location has a history in this community.
這麼說 他希望毀掉地標 毀掉普羅維頓斯的一部分歷史
So he wants to destroy landmarks, Pieces of providence's history.
所以才隨機選擇受害者 這才是他的意圖
That's why the random victims. He's making a point.
很可能是對這個城市 極深怨恨的一種表現
Probably the manifestation Of a deep hatred for the city.
他要在所有人都知道 都會去的地方留下傷痕
He wants to scar the places Everybody knows and goes to.
也不盡然 跟我走
Not quite. Take a ride with me.
- 我們去看看其他的犯罪現場 - 為什麼?
- We're gonna have a look at the other crime scenes. - Why?
就依我的吧
Indulge me.
襲擊一處公共設施 所有人都會有反應
Attack an institution,everybody responds.
左鄰右舍的人都出來了 市長也會部署額外的警力
Neighbors come out, the mayor assigns extra cops.
一個敬神的地方 成了犯罪現場 於自身感情而言 也像是遭到了侵犯
A place of worship turns into a crime scene, You feel personally assaulted.
這正中他下懷 公正的反應 公眾強烈的呼聲
That's what gets him off. The response. Public outcry.
他想要把事情搞大
He wants the big show.
你覺得他會重訪犯罪現場?
You think he's revisiting the crime scenes?
不只是重訪 是重新體會
Not just revisiting. Reliving.
他找到了一種方法 能使自己的兇案 永遠"新鮮" 因為這是留給城市的傷疤
He's found a way to keep the murders he's committed Fresh because they're always on the city's mind.
目擊者說都沒看到案發過程
"witnesses say they didn't see it happen,
是聽到受害者妻女的尖叫聲 才注意到的
Were alerted by the screams of the victim's wife and daughter."
在教堂 活生生地滅口
Man alive,in a church.
這傢伙 簡直膽大包天了
This guy,he ain't afraid onothin'.
有什麼要帶的嗎? 我要去抽根煙
Need anything? I'm gonna grab a smoke.
當心Connie 那玩意會要你的命的
Careful,connie,those things'll kill ya.
普羅維頓斯警署社區分局
小心 那很燙
Careful,it's hot.
真好 我很愛熱茶喲
Oh,good. 'cause I love my tea really warm.
想在你的茶堣]加點奶油和糖嗎?
Would you like some cream and sugar with your tea,too?
請
Please.
Tuffet小姐也愛這麼喝茶
That's how miss tuffet likes her tea,too.
謝謝你
Thank you.
很好喝
It's good.
但我覺得Sophia的茶要更好喝一點
But I think sophia's tea is a little bit better.
謝謝
Thank you.
你有幾個?
How many do you have?
你配合得這麼好 不可能不是個當媽的人
You're too good at this not to be a mom.
一個 男孩
One. A boy.
Sophia第一次聖餐本來應該在下周的
Sophia's first communion is supposed to be next week.
她會做得很好的 不好意思
She'll do great. Excuse me.
嘿 Rossi
Hey,rossi.
我們準備好馬上要給出側寫了 但我有點事情需要你做
We're just getting ready to deliver the profile, But I need you to do something.
我明白
I understand.
好的 嗯 要是有進一步發現 給我打電話 再見
Ok,uh,call me when you find out more. Bye.
Sophia 媽媽跟Jareau探員 要單獨待會 好嗎?
Sophia,mommy and agent jareau need some privacy,ok?
- 謝謝你的茶 - 不客氣
- Thank you for the tea. - You're welcome.
我明白那個語氣
I know that tone of voice.
接下來總會跟著壞消息
It's always followed by bad news.
你該知道 有很多這種人 需要覺得自己很強大
You should know a lot of these guys need to feel powerful.
製造公眾事件 能夠賦予他們某種驕傲的感覺
Producing a spectacle gives them that sense of pride.
我在試著通過控制 外面的媒體來消除它
I'm trying to quell that by controlling the circus outside.
他在看著我們嗎?
Is he watching us?
也許 我們認為他會重訪他的作案現場
Maybe. We think he revisits his crime scenes.
媒體很有可能會把他吸引過來
It's possible the media could have brought him here.
如果他真的來了 不會是來和我女兒握手的
He won't shake my daughter's hand this time if he does.
我們建議警方將不明嫌犯 作為縱火犯看待 而非割喉殺人犯
We suggest that youve think of this unsub Not as a slasher but as an arsonist.
因為他所獲得的滿足感 並非來自實施犯罪的實際行動
Because the gratification he's getting Isn't from the physical act of murder
而是公眾對此的反應
But from the public's reaction to it.
縱火犯通過縱火 將關注轉移到自己身上
Arsonists draw attention to themselves Through the fires they set.
他們選擇的地點 對自身具有很強的象徵意義
這個不明嫌犯永遠不會真正縱火 卻和縱火犯有著相同的心理
While this unsub will never set an actual fire, He has the same psychosis as one who does.
我們的不明嫌犯符合那個模式
Our unsub fits that model.
他選擇的作案地點 都是社區的重要地段
His locations have been pillars of the community.
殺誰並不那麼重要 而在大家最愛的 餐館外 或做禮拜的地方行兇
The victims he picks aren't as important as the effect Of killing them
所造成的影響才是最重要的
outside of your favorite restaurant Or place of worship.
他選擇目擊者著最多的地方
By picking locales wit the highest visibility,
那麼散播的恐懼也達到了極限
He's creating the highest level of fear in that neighborhood,
這樣更強化了他強大的自我感覺
Which reinforces his feeling of power.
雖說這樣 但縱火犯並不以傷害為目的
Yeah,but arsonists don't set out to hurt people.
- 這傢伙卻以此為目的 - 沒錯
- This guy clearly does. - That's true.
該不明嫌犯絕對屬於 反社會性格類型
And this unsub Definitely falls in the category of sociopath.
受害者只是他完成任務的必要犧牲品
His victims are there only to achieve his goal.
他並不會對他們產生同情
He doesn't have the ability to empathize with them.
對他來說 他們僅僅是他的工具 和一罐汽油一支火柴沒什麼區別
To him,they're just tools for him to use, No different than a can of gasoline and a match.
等會兒打給你 親愛的 我正在市場呢
I'll talk to you later,sweetie. I'm just at the market right now.
好吧 我也愛你
All right. I love you,too.
但他的殺人手法能給我們啟示
But even how he kills tells us something.
從視覺上而言 割喉是髒亂的行為
Slashing a throat is a messy,visual act.
純粹是為了吸引注意 就如一場大火
It's designed to create attention, Just like a fire.
縱火犯通常是使命型的
Arsonists are often ssion based.
他們需要確認上一場火燒盡了 才進行下一場縱火
They need make sure their first fire has burnt out Before they set another one.
- 這些是有機的嗎? - 是的
- Are these organic? - Yeah.
我記得後面的推車媮晹酗@束更新鮮的 稍等一下
You know,I think I have a fresher bunch of those Back in the truck. Holdn one second.
他們高度遵守紀律 非常專心
They're also highly disciplined and focused.
如果環境不適宜縱火 或對此兇手而言 不適宜割喉 他們會繼續等待
If conditions aren't right to set a fire, Or in this case,slash a throat, they'll move on.
不好意思 沒有了
You know,I'm sorry,I don't.
但今天真是你的幸運日呢
Which actually makes this your lucky day.
如果想要點其他什麼 這些繡球花再適合不過了
If you want to get something else, These hydrangeas are perfect.
它們正需要主人呢 我半價賣給你
They have to go home with somebody. I'll give them to you for half.
真的很美 就要這個了
They're beautiful. absolutely,I'll take them.
藍色就像你的眼睛一樣美 怎麼樣?
Blue for your eyes. How about that?
儘管他需要殺人 他知道自製
In addition to his need to kill, He has self-control.
他會有一段冷靜期 因為他十分享受所作所為
He has a short cooling off period Because he's enjoying what he's doing.
這反過來滿足了他的自我 讓他更好地掩蓋罪行
This in turn feeds his ego And keeps him covering his tracks.
也就令他更加危險
This makes him even more dangerous.
如果他感覺沮喪 遇到太多障礙
If he gets frustrated, encounters too many obstacles,
或者他的自戀遭到打擊 他可能開始瘋狂屠殺
Or suffers a blow to his narcissistic ego, he could go on an all-out rampage.
注意待業的人
Focus on men between jobs.
他正在尋找下一個作案地點 而非繼續工作
Instead of working consistently, He is hunting at his next location.
他會重遊案發地 我們建議你們...
and he's revisiting his old scenes.We recommend you--
喂
Yeah.
記者們離開Collins家了
The news crews are leaving the collins house.
- 他又作案了 - 是 第三街和謝爾比街的農貿市場
- He's killed again. - Yeah. Farmers market at third and shelby.
媒體已經趕去了
The press are already on their way.
我們能利用這一點 這能滿足他的自我意識 他會留下觀察的
We could use that. It'll feed his ego. He'll want to stay and watch.
各位 到達犯罪現場後 我需要大家仔細檢查人群
Ladies and gentlemen, when you get to the crime scene, We need you to canvass the crowd.
特別留意那些對現場更感興趣 不關心受害者的圍觀者
Pay particular attention to onlookers who might be More interested in the scene itself than the victim.
給每個人照相 抱歉
And get photographs of everyone. Excuse me.
JJ 我需要你過去
Jj,I need you there.
不 Hotch 我... 我不能走
No,hotch,I-- I can't leave.
JJ你要去控制媒體
Jj,you're there to control the media.
他們過去報道犯罪現場了 這會令不明嫌疑犯分心的
They've left to cover the crime scene, Which may distract the unsub.
我們能抓住他的 現在需要你去掌控那些媒體
We can catch him, but I need you on top of the press
確保它們關注的是我們的目標 而非不明嫌犯
Making sure they're focud on our goals and not the unsub's.
- JJ - 好吧 我馬上就去
- Jj. - Yeah. I'm on my way.
我很抱歉
I'm so sor.
沒關係 我也理解這種語氣
It's ok. I know that tone of voice,too.
- 有人死了嗎? - 哦 我的上帝
- Somebody died? - H,my god.
怎麼了?
What happened?
我猜是那個刺客
I bet it was that stabber.
刺客? 什麼刺客?
Stabber? What stabber?
那個在鎮上到處割人喉嚨的傢伙
You know,the y who's been cutting People's throats open around town.
是啊 那傢伙
Right. Him.
- 請和我來一下先生 來吧 - 怎麼了? 什麼?
- Come with me,sir.Come on.Come on. - What? Wait,what?
我們走 普羅維頓斯警局的
Let's go. Providence pole.
說吧 Emily
Go ahead,emily.
嘿 Rossi 我在這兒發現一串血跡 但是還沒找到刀
Hey,rossi,I got a trail of blood here, But I haven't found the knife yet.
他逃跑了 看看血跡在哪兒中斷的
He ran away. See where it ends.
明白
Got it.
- 我們不能在當地播放這些 - 播放? 早就報道完了
- We can't run this locally. - Run? It's ran,it's gone.
- CNN在3小時內登做頭條了 - 把影響降到最低
- Cnn's leading with this in 3 hours. - Minimize his impact.
不要給他取綽號 這樣只會鼓勵他殺得更多
Do not give him a name. It'll just encourage him to kill more.
這是讓我們 全程跟蹤報道的交換條件?
Am I making this deal for full access?
當然
Of course.
只要稱讚當地警方的工作 忽略我們
Just attribute the good work to the providence p.D.And leave us out of it.
他是個在這兒工作的好人
He was just a nice guy who worked here.
我以前見過他 但從沒買過他的東西
I'd en him here before but never bought anything from him.
關於襲擊你還記得什麼?
What do you remember about the attack?
我問他 這些花是否是有機種植的
I asked if his flowers were organic.
我轉身 接下來就我就感覺到 一些熱熱的東西 是血
I turned away,and the next thing I know I felt something warm. It was blood.
你看見持刀的人了嗎?
Did you get a look at the guy with the knife?
我看見的第一個人是呼救的人 他試圖去止血
The first person I saw was a guy screaming for help And he was trying to stop the bleeding.
一群人跑過來幫忙 我想我當時只是站著尖叫
A bunch of people ran over there trying to help, And I think I just stood there screaming.
往回說一點 是誰在呼救?
Back up for a second. Who was shouting?
我不知道 一個小伙子
I don't know,some guy.
當我轉過身來 他正扶著那可憐的人 試圖引起大家注意
When I turned around, he was holding the poor man up, Trying to get someone to notice.
這傢伙身上肯定有很多血 對嗎?
This guy must have got a lot of blood on him,yeah?
是的 我想是當然的
Yeah,sure,I guess.
好的 謝謝你 警官
All right,thank you for your time. Officer.
說吧 Emily
go ahead,emily.
- 我找到血跡終止的地方 - 然後?
- I found out where that blood trail ended. - And?
不明嫌犯換了衣服
The unsub changed his clothes.
他把血浸透的衣服扔在垃圾箱
He left his bloo d-soaked ones here in the trash.
他開始避免沾血上身 發生什麼事了?
He's avoided getting blood on himself up to now. What changed?
我也不知道 但無論如何 他是有預謀的
I don't know,but whatever his reason, He came prepared.
他知道這次會有很多血
He knew he would be bloody this time.
我待會打給你 你那兒怎麼樣 Morgan?
I'll get back to you. What do you got,morgan?
一位目擊者說 第一個做出反應的人 是一位市民 刺殺後大概2秒就開始呼救
A witness says the first responder,a citizen, Cried out for help maybe 2 seconds after the stabbing.
- 他就是不明嫌犯 - 我也這麼認為
- He was the unsub. - I think so.
他不再滿足於重訪犯罪現場了 他想要成為現場的一部分
He's not content with revisiting the crime scene anymore, He needs to be part of them.
- 警探 - 是的
- Detective! - Yeah.
市場周圍進行封鎖
Establish a perimeter around the market.
每20英尺要保證有你的人
Put your men no more an 20 feet apart.
每個警察都要在彼此視線之內
Every cop needs to be in sight of one another.
稍等 怎麼回事兒?
Whoa,wait a minute. What?
- 不明嫌犯還在這兒 - 你肯定嗎?
- The unsub is still here. - Are you sure?
先把男女分開
Start by separating the men from the women.
我們發現了丟棄的衣服 靠這個來找他
We found discarded clothes. That's how we find him.
- 我們按體型核對 - 好的 馬上就去 Gardella 快來
- We match by body type. - All right,I'm on it. Gardella,come on.
收到
Copy that.
Connor 是你嗎?
Connor,is that you?
- 嘿 Liddy - 你去哪兒?
- Hey,liddy. - What are you going?
我要回餐廳了
I gotta get back to the diner.
你得遲到了 所有人都要留在現場
Well,you're gonna be late. We gotta detain everyone inside here.
不是吧 那不就沒人做漢堡了?
Oh,come on. How many hamburgers have let slide?
聽話 夥計 走吧
Just following orders,buddy. Let's go.
我遲到的話你得跟Sal解釋
You gotta explain to sal when I'm late.
行了 你的客人不會餓死的
Yeah,yeah,your customers won't starve.
這也得貼在板子上嗎?
Those gotta be on the board,too?
FBI又出了個好主意啊
What's the next great bit of advice from the fbi,huh?
別這樣 Gardella 生氣也得分時候
Take it easy,gardella. This ain't the time or the place.
要是不聽他們的 Liddy這會兒還能和我喝咖啡呢
If we hadn't listened to them,liddy and I would be havg our morning cup of coffee.
我們推測他是以任務為指引的 這次殺戮不符合這個模式
We profiled that he was mission oriented, And this kill doesn't fit that pattern.
殺害Liddy警官明顯違背了常規
The murder of officer liddy is a significant departure
儘管這個不明嫌犯很反覆無常
Even for someone as unpredictable as this unsub.
這是出於自衛本能的謀殺 為了脫身
This was a murder of self-preservation, just to get away.
地點也不是慣常所選 沒人圍觀
This location is not his m.O., Secludedwith no audience,
- 刀刺 而不是刀割 - 所以呢?
- stabbing,not cutting. - So?
所以他現在在街上尋找下一個受害者
So he's out prowling the streets right now Looking for another victim
然後所有人都會注意他
so the city will pay atteion to him.
你們提供了一系列地點
You've been handed a list of locations
是我們認為會吸引不明嫌犯的
That we think might be of particular interest to the unsub.
你們需要在這些地方加強警力
We're asking you to double and even triple your surveillance in these areas.
多留點神 兄弟們
Keep your wits about you,guys.
- 警探 我們有話跟你說 - 好的
- Detective,we'd like to speak to you. - Sure.
就這樣吧 夥計們 謝謝
That's it,fellas. Thank you.
警探 這件事和Liddy警官有關
Detective,the story has become about officer liddy.
我們得把注意力放回不明嫌犯身上 不然他恐怕會失控
We need to get the attention back on the unsub Or we're afraid that he may lash out.
目前為止 不明嫌犯還足夠安分 避免在不當的時機殺人
Up till now,the unsub has been disciplined enough To avoid killing if the circumstances weren't right.
就像有人在的時候縱火犯不會放火
Like an arsonist who won't set a fire if there's someone there
以免煙從窗口冒出來的時候被發現
To see him leaving while smoke is billowing out the windows.
要是有棟樓沒有著火呢?
What if we say that one of the buildings didn't burn?
不明嫌犯會作何反應?
How would the unsub react to that?
他必然會故地重遊 再去縱火
He'd be compelled to come back and finish the job.
那我們就選一處之前的罪案現場 讓他看到公眾聚集在那
Then we pick one of the previous locations, Show that the community has rallied around it,
並不怕他
那我們要找個對他來說 最有象徵意義的地方
So we need to find a location With the greatest symbolism up to this point.
很簡單
That's easy.
我們以城市故去的英雄激勵大家
And we use the city's fallen hero As inspiration.
要找警長或者市長發表聲明嗎?
Should we get the chief of police or the mayor To make a statement?
那樣更能鼓舞人心
It could help with inspiring people.
我們有更好的選擇
We've got something better.
Collins上尉的遺孀
Captain collins' widow.
我不能要求她做這種事
I--I cannot ask her to do that.
她很受關注 全城的人都會同情她
She's highly visible,and she's someone With whom the entire city can sympathize.
如果她讓城堣H克服恐懼到教堂去 不明嫌犯不會忽略這一點的
When she tells the city not to be afraid to come back to church, The unsub can't ignore that.
要是這麼做 引得不明嫌犯去找Meg呢?
And what happens if this draws the unsub to meg?
我們會和她在一起
We keep her with us.
我們會抓住那個混蛋
We'll take the bastard down.
- 你想讓我對著鏡頭念這個? - 是的
- You want me to read this, In front of cameras? - Yes.
殺害我丈夫的兇手也會看到?
Will my husband's killer be there?
很可能他會在電視上看到
Most likely he'll watch it on tv.
會有警察時刻保護你
You'll have police protection around you at all times.
不 我不幹
No. I won't do it.
Meg 拜託了 我們需要你
Meg,please. We need you.
你代表了Paul的記憶
You represent paul's memory.
我代表著Sophia Paul已經犧牲了 我也付出了很多
I represent sophia. Paul's given enough. So have I.
是的 我知道了 謝謝
Yes,sir. No,I understand. Thank you.
是市長 他說他不會批准 在聖阿爾維納教堂召開發佈會
That was the mayor. He won't sign off on a press conference At st. Alvina.
JJ也沒能說服Meg Collins
And jj couldn't make any headway with meg collins.
Liddy警官遇刺是什麼時候的事?
How long has it been since officer liddy was stabbed?
16小時以前
16 hours.
如果不明嫌犯出去瘋狂行兇 他現在應該已經得手了
Well,if the unsub was going to go out on a spree, He would have done it by now.
為什麼他還沒得逞?
Why hasn't he?
- 他殺了一個警察 他在避風頭 - 有可能
- He killed a cop. He's laying low. - May be.
但是我們的側寫說他更像縱火犯
But we've profiled this guy like an arsonist.
重要的是後果 不是過程
It's the aftermath that matters, not the act.
你是說他轉而滿足於警方的悲痛?
You think he's feeding off the grief of the police department instead?
這樣一來 他就有了新的目標
If so,then he's found something new to get off on.
- 警探 - 稍等 怎麼了?
- Detective. - Hold on a second. Yeah?
我需要一份名單 列出你們的警員聚眾的地方
I need a list of establishments Where your officers socialize--
比如酒吧 餐館 檯球廳 只要能想到的
Bars,restaunts,pool halls, everything you've got.
沒問題 Eddie 我等會兒打給你
Sure,right. Eddie,let me get back to you.
- 再來一杯 夥計們? - 好吧 反正下班了
- Another round,guys? - Yeah. We're off the clock anays.
兄弟們 這杯是為了Liddy
One more for liddy,boys.
致偉大的警察
Here's to a great cop.
我們會替你抓住那小子的 Joe
We'll get this bastard for you,oe.
FBI會幫你們嗎?
Yeah,the fbi gonna help you do that?
不用側寫也知道我們找的是什麼人
We don't need a profile to know the kind of gu we're dealing with.
一個懦夫
A coward.
他趁黑捅死一個警察 然後逃之夭夭
He stabs a cop in the dark And runs away like a vermin.
- 沒種 - 別逗了
- Gutless. - No kiddin'.
同志們 我找到很多警察的好去處 還有用工記錄
Comrades,I have amassed employment records for police hangouts.
- 要查什麼? - 白種人 男性 25到30歲
- What do you want me toook for? - White males 25 to 30.
忒少了吧
I'm gonna need more than that.
縱火犯通常與母親關係更親密
Arsonists typically have a stronger relationship With their mothers than their fathers,
查查單身母親的家庭 有過虐待 離異 或者家庭暴力
So let's look for single-mother households With a history of abuse, bad divorce,or paternal violence.
Garcia 兒子的記錄也要查 比如進過少管所 小偷小摸
Manifestations in the son,too,garcia, Like juvenile arrests,heavy crimes,
- 還有成績明顯下降 - 謝了寶貝兒 這還差不多
- A significant drop in grades. - Thank you,boys. That will do.
我看就是他了
Oh,this looks like something.
找到什麼了?
What do you have?
Connor O'Brien 他的父親被捕入獄
Connor o'brien.His dad went to prison for--
天吶 他不只放火燒了孩兒他媽的住處
Oh,lordy--not only setting mom's apartment on fire
還偽裝成意外事故 以獲取保險
But making it look like it was an accident So he could collect on the insurance.
為了幾毛錢殺了孩子的母親?
Rned his kid's mother for a few bucks?
Connor出庭作證了 他那時才十歲
Yeah. And then connor testified. He was 10.
O'Brien現在在哪兒?
Where's o'brien now?
他在Quality咖啡館工作
He works at the quality cafe.
- 就在街對過 - Garcia 謝謝
- Guys,it's across the street. - Thanks,garcia.
FBI Connor O'Brien在哪兒?
Fbi.Where's connor o'brien?
Connie? 他走了有10分鐘吧
Connie? He just stepped out about 10 minutes ago.
知道他去哪兒了嗎?
Did you see which way he went?
抽煙去了吧 怎麼了?
He just went out to grab a smoke.Why?
Garcia 幫我查O'Brien家的地址
Garcia,I need o'brien's home address.
你們在這兒幹嘛呢?
What are you guys doing here?
下班了 到這邊喝一杯 紀念一下Liddy
We were done with our shifts. We poured one out for liddy.
你們給他講最新的這起謀殺了?
Did you talk to him about the recent mders?
當然了 我們說我們會抓住這個膽小鬼
Of course. We said we'd catch the coward.
- 你鄙視他了 - Admiral街1121號 16號房
- You disparaged him. - 1121 admiral,apartment 16.
在城市的另一邊
It's the other side of town.
Dave 你和Morgan跟 Prentiss還有特警隊到嫌犯家會合
Dave,you and morgan meet prentiss and s.W.A.T.On site.
Connor O'Brien!
Connor o'brien!
沒人!
Clear!
他不會回來了
He's not coming back here.
他會發起最後一擊
He's gonna make his last stand.
但他還是關心 自己是不是大家最關注的人物
He's still gonna need to know he's foremost on everyone's mind.
過來這邊!
Guys!
他收集了所有關於他母親之死的報道
It looks like he's got every article that was printed About his mom's death.
還有他葬禮上的禱告卡
He has the prayer card from her funeral.
生日卡
Birthday cards.
簽名都是她母親的 沒有他父親的
Look,all of them signed by his mom, not by his father.
看這張照片 絕對是滿腔仇恨
Look at this. That's a lot of hate.
他爸已經進監獄了 所以他不可能殺他爹
His old man is already in prison. He can't attack him.
於是他要毀掉那些 能讓他想起父親的地方
So he goes after the places that remind him of his father.
他跟他父親溝通的方式只能是通過暴力
The only way he can get through to his dad is with violence.
William O'Brien 又名Billy Os
William o'brien,aka billy os.
社交關係很豐富 擅長利用電線短路造成嚴重火災
Was a connected guy who specialized in turning faulty wiring Into a 3-alarm fire.
Connor的證詞 使他因為殺妻被判終身監禁
Because of connor's testimony, He was given a life sentence For the murder of his wife,
但最近被減刑到5年內可申請假釋
But it was recently reduced To theossibility of parole in 5 years.
- 什麼時候減的刑? - 一個月前
- When was the sentence reduced? - One month ago.
正好在兇殺案開始之前 這是導火索
Just before the murders started. There's our stressor.
如果他爸爸已經進監獄了 他為什麼要這樣向他報復呢?
Why would he do this to get back at his father if he's already in jail?
必須有人付出代價
Somebody's gotta pay.
他現在不再弱小了
He's a tough guy now.
醒醒!
Hey,wake up. Wake up!
你媽死了
Your mother's dead.
該走了
Time to go.
- 可是 爸爸你說了我可以... - 我說該走了!
- But,dad,you said I could-- - I said let's go!
沒事的寶貝兒
It's ok,honey.
再等我一下下 我們一會兒就走啦
Just give me one more minute, we'll be out of here.
好的 謝謝你 Eddie
Yeah,thanks,eddie.
媽的
Damn it.
- 是哪? - 一英里外的圖書館
- Where? - Library about a mile from here.
人們發現的時候小寶寶守著媽媽哭呢
Mother was found next to her crying baby.
孩子有事兒麼?
Is the baby ok?
沒事兒 可是現場沒有找到刀子
Not a scratch,but they haven't found the knife yet.
現在他陷在了自己的回憶中 他會不停地殺更多的人
It's his memento now. He won't stop until he's killed As may people as possible.
我們還是應該回到我們最初的計劃 要製造一個他不能拒絕的誘惑
We have to go to our original plan-- Create an event he can't resist coming to.
要讓他相信他還沒有成功
He has to believe he was unsuccessful.
他不會回到自己的公寓了 我覺得他也不會再去犯罪現場
If he won't go bk to his apartment, and I don't think He's gonna revisit the crime scenes.
在圖書館被殺的母親 她已經死了?
The mother from the library? She's already gone.
當場失血過多而死 醫護人員已經沒在搶救了
She bled out at the scene. The emts stopped working on her.
告訴他們繼續搶救
Tell them to keep trying to resuscitate her.
- 可是她已經死了 - 但是不明嫌犯不知道
- But she's dead. - Yeah,but the unsub doesn't know that.
告訴媒體她沒有死 她還在和死神搏鬥
Tell the press she made it, she's hanging on for dear life.
今天晚上組織大家點蠟燭為她守夜
And we organize a candlelight vigil for her tonight.
如果他一定要完成自己的使命 卻發現她還沒死 他會回來殺她的
If he's mission oriented and he thinks she's still alive, He'll have to come back for her.
然後我們就可以抓住他
And we'll be there.
告訴受害人的丈夫這是怎麼回事兒 這樣他不會一頭霧水
Let the husband know what's going on So he's aware.
讓媒體都去圖書館  告訴他們現場直播 盡量關注我們的行動
Have the press there. Tell them to go live And to keep the focus on us as much as they can.
Collins夫人
Mrs. Collins.
剛剛被襲擊的那個女人...
The woman who was just attacked...
她是位母親是麼?
She was a mother?
對
Yes.
有什麼我可以幫忙的麼?
What can I do to help?
我們在最新的犯罪現場為大家進行直播 看起來 FBI正在...
We are live at the latest crime scene, Where the fbi is facilitating what appears to be...
警官們! 讓這些人挪到轉角處 不要讓他們越過警戒線
Officer! Move this crowd to that corner And pin them behind the police barricades.
女性 大約30歲 喉部割傷 還有生命
We've got a female about 30, Her throat's been slashed,she's hanging on.
醫院有血管外科醫生待命
There's a vascular surgeon standing by at the hospital.
給 找你一塊 兩塊 謝謝
Yeah,one,two is your change. Thank you.
您需要什麼?
Can I help you?
一包煙 呃 能不能開大點聲?
A pack of smokes. Uh,c-could you turn that up?
...犯罪現場 FBI正在組織...
Crime scene, where the fbi is facilitating
搶救最新的一位被害人
What appears to be a rescue attempt of the most recent victim.
他們將她迅速送上了救護車
They are rushing her into an ambulance now.
讓一下 謝謝!
Make some room,please!
這邊走 她怎麼樣了?
Right this way,guys. How's she doing?
- 情況已經穩定了 長官 - 他們過來了 請讓開
- We've got her stabilized,sir. - They're coming through. Please clear it out.
請讓開一條路 謝謝
Can we clear a path,please.
警官們 請派五輛警車護送救護車去醫院
Officers,I want a 5-car escort for the ambulance To the hospital.
我們可以看到 被害人還活著 正被火速送往醫院
As you can see,she is still alive And being rushed to the hospital now.
看來她沒事了
Looks like she's ok.
不不 不可能的
No,no,that's im-- that's not possible.
大家可能都知道 我的丈夫  Paul Collins上尉 上週日遇害
As many of you know, My husband captain paul collins Was murdered this past Sunday.
你們給我的支持令我很受鼓舞
The support I have received has been inspiring.
這也是為什麼我現在希望大家都來支持 剛剛受到襲擊的Julia Vecchia
Which is why I'm asking everyone To support the latest victim,julia vecchia,
她正在聖弗雷澤醫院 不懈地和死神做著鬥爭
Who is fighting for her life right now at st. Frazier's hospital.
是那個被殺的大兵的妻子
It's that wife of the soldier who got killed.
我代表我丈夫 呼籲大家都到聖弗雷澤醫院
On behalf of my husband, We are asking you to come together At st.Frazier's
為她秉燭祈福
to hold a candlelight vigil tonight.
為了重塑我們這個偉大的城市的信心
Please help restore this great city...
你看她 好堅強的姑娘
Look at her. Kid's got a lot of heart.
謝謝
Thank you.
- 你覺得這會管用麼? - 會的
- You think this'll work? - It should.
現在我們已經把公眾的注意力 從Conner身上轉到了被害人身上
We've shifted the public's focus From connor to his victim.
這應該會讓他很生氣 他會有所動作的
That should make him angry enough to show up And try to do something about it.
嫌犯出現
- Connor O'Brien? - 行動 行動
- Connor o'brien? - Roll in now. Go,go.
把手舉起來 趴下!
Puyour hands where I can see them and get down on the ground!
FBI!
Fbi!
站住!
Stop right there!
別動! 不要反抗!
Stop! Moving! Stop fightg!
不要反抗!
Stop fighting! Stop!
夠了! 一切都結束了! 不要反抗了!
That's enough! It's over! That's enough!
她死了! 她不可能還活著的!
She's dead! There no possible way she could have survived!
Connor O'Brien 你被捕了
Connor o'brien,you're under arrest.
我們知道你為什麼會來 你知道麼?
We know why you came down here. Do you?
我必須要確定一下 她死了 對吧?
I had to make sure. She--she's dead,right?
你笑什麼? 你要進監獄了
What are you smiling at? You're going to jail.
在監獄 殺過警察的人會得到帝王般的待遇
In jail they treat cop killers like kings.
那你知道在警局塈A是什麼待遇麼?
First you gotta see how we treat 'em at the station.
把他拖下去
Get him out of here.
真難以置信 他那麼需要關注
It's hard to believe that guy was so starved for attention
他殺了那麼多人 就為了趕上他爹
That he murdered all those people just to one-up s father.
Moreland警探給我講了 Connor的爸爸Billy Os
I spokwith detective moreland about connor's father billy os.
他說老一點的警察都知道這傢伙惹不得
He said the older police knew to give him a wide berth.
他不說話則已 一旦發話 所有人就都得乖乖聽著
He didn't say much,but when he did... People listened.
成人版的校霸
The adult version of a bully.
可是要擊敗父親的方法有很多啊
There are lots of ways that sons defeat their fathers.
我就不斷讀各種博士學位
I just keep getting ph.D.S.
一個反社會的人的兒子有可能超過他爹麼?
Does the son of a sociopath ever really have a chance?
O'Brien和他爸爸犯的罪是同一類的
You know,o'brien committed his crimes in the same jurisdiction as his father.
他倆被送到同一個監獄只是時間問題
It's only a matter of time before he's put in the same prison.
你的第一次聖餐
莎士比亞寫道 "父為子付出 雙方皆喜"
William shakespeare wrote, "when a father gives to his son, they both laugh.
"子為父付出 雙方皆悲"
"when a son gives to his father, Both cry."
老爸
Hey,dad.
唉喲喲
Well,well,well.
你媽知道你在這兒不?
Does your mother know you're here?
犯罪心理 第五季 第15集 全民公敵
== 結束 ==
Criminal Minds Season05 Episode15 Public Enemy